# **Daniele Giardiello**

• Address: Italy

**Gender:** Male **Date of birth:** 28/11/1988 **Nationality:** Italian

## **ABOUT ME**

Statistician | Data scientist with robust experience in research and statistical consulting in various international research institutes and private companies. R / SAS / STATA programmer with strong passion in statistical consulting to support researchers in their statistical analyses. Extremely curious to actively know new skills through challenging learning.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[ 06/04/2021 - Current ] **Biomedical data scientist / Biostatistician (home-based)** 

**EURAC research** <a href="https://www.eurac.edu/en">https://www.eurac.edu/en</a>

**City:** Bolzano/Bozen **Country:** Italy

Main activities and responsibilities:

Biomedical data scientist and statistical consultant in the field of biomedical research

especially about COVID-19 disease. Temporary contract till April 2022.

# [ 15/11/2016 - 28/02/2021 ] PhD candidate in biostatistics - Expected PhD defense June-July 2022

The Netherlands Cancer Institute (NKI) and Leiden University Medical Center (LUMC) https://www.nki.nl/divisions/molecular-pathology/schmidt-m-group/

Address: Amsterdam and Leiden, Netherlands

**City:** Amsterdam **Country:** Netherlands

Name of unit or department: Molecular Pathology (in NKI), Biomedical data sciences (in

LUMC)

**Business or sector:** Professional, scientific and technical activities

## Main activities and responsibilities:

Main goal: build, validate and assess the prediction performance and the clinical utility of a contralateral breast cancer risk prediction model using time-to-event models with competing risks using individual patient data (more than 100,000 patients) from multiple studies in presence of sporadic and systematic missing data.

#### Main activities:

- Data management and R/SAS/STATA programming also using High Performance Computing (HPC);
- Experience in Real World Data coming from different international sources;
- Reading scientific literature especially medical statistics and applied medical research papers;
- Statistical consulting for researchers and statistical teaching;
- Writing peer review scientific manuscripts;
- Provide statistical reports using Rmarkdown and GitHub.

Supervisors: prof. Marjanka K Schmidt and prof. Ewout W Steyerberg
Title of the dissertation: "Prediction of contralateral breast cancer - Statistical aspects and performance assessment"

# [ 01/07/2016 - 30/09/2016 ] **Statistician**

OPIS srl <a href="https://opisresearch.com/">https://opisresearch.com/</a>

Address: 20832, Desio (Monza and Brianza), Italy

City: Desio
Country: Italy

Business or sector: Professional, scientific and technical activities

Main activities and responsibilities:

Overall description: biostatistician working in clinical trials (phase II-III).

## Main activities:

- SAS programming;
- Revising Case Report Forms (CRFs);
- Proving listings, figures, and tables.

## [ 09/2014 - 06/2016 ] **Statistician**

Italian National Cancer Institute <a href="https://www.istitutotumori.mi.it/en/home">https://www.istitutotumori.mi.it/en/home</a>

Address: 20133, Milan, Italy

City: Milan
Country: Italy

Name of unit or department: Clinicial Epidemiology and Clinical Trials organization

Business or sector: Professional, scientific and technical activities

Main activities and responsibilities:

Statistical consulting in medical research;

R/SAS programming;

Supporting research in statistical medical writing;

## [ 04/2013 - 09/2014 ] **Statistician**

# The Lombardy and Emilia Romagna Experimental Zootechnic Institute <a href="https://www.izsler.it/">https://www.izsler.it/</a>

Address: 25124, Brescia, Italy

**City:** Brescia **Country:** Italy

Business or sector: Professional, scientific and technical activities

Main activities and responsibilities:

Statistical consulting and support for veterinary research;

Epidemiological surveillance;

Spatial statistics;

# EDUCATION AND TRAINING

# [ 10/2010 - 11/2012 ] MSc in Biostatistics and Experimental Statistics (summa cum laude)

Address: Milan, Italy

# [ 10/2007 - 09/2010 ] BSc in Statistical Science and information management (summa cum laude)

University of Milan - Bicocca <a href="https://en.unimib.it/">https://en.unimib.it/</a>

Address: Milan, Italy

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Italian

Other language(s):

## **English**

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

## **Dutch**

LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2** 

# PUBLICATIONS List of all publications in pubmed https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=daniele+giardiello&sort=date&size=100 DRIVING LICENCE Cars: B

## HOBBIES AND INTER-ESTS

## **Hobbies and interests**

Running, nature, music, hospital clowning